{
    "cards": [
        {
            "id": "1",
            "question": "ls",
            "answer": "Directory listing"
        },
        {
            "id": "2",
            "question": "ls -al",
            "answer": "Formatted listing with hidden files"
        },
        {
            "id": "3",
            "question": "cd dir ",
            "answer": "Change directory"
        },
        {
            "id": "4",
            "question": "cd",
            "answer": "Change to home"
        },
        {
            "id": "5",
            "question": "pwd",
            "answer": "Show current directory"
        },
        {
            "id": "6",
            "question": "mkdir dir",
            "answer": "Create directory dir"
        },
        {
            "id": "7",
            "question": "rm file",
            "answer": "Delete file"
        },
        {
            "id": "8",
            "question": "rm -r dir",
            "answer": "Delete directory dir"
        },
        {
            "id": "9",
            "question": "rm -r file",
            "answer": "Force remove file"
        },
        {
            "id": "10",
            "question": "rm -rf dir",
            "answer": "Force remove directory dir"
        },
        {
            "id": "11",
            "question": "cp file1 file2",
            "answer": "Copy file1 to file2"
        },
        {
            "id": "12",
            "question": "cp -r dir1 dir2",
            "answer": "Copy dir1 to dir2;create dir2 if it doesn't exist"
        },
        {
            "id": "13",
            "question": "mv file1 file2",
            "answer": "Rename or move file1 to file2 if file2 is an existing directory,moves file1 into directory file2"
        },
        {
            "id": "14",
            "question": "ln -s file link",
            "answer": "Create symbolic link to file"
        },
        {
            "id": "15",
            "question": "touch file",
            "answer": "Create or update file"
        },
        {
            "id": "16",
            "question": "cat > file",
            "answer": "Places standard input into file"
        },
        {
            "id": "17",
            "question": "more file",
            "answer": "Output the contents of file"
        },
        {
            "id": "18",
            "question": "head file",
            "answer": "Output the first 10 lines of file"
        },
        {
            "id": "19",
            "question": "tail file",
            "answer": "Output the last 10 lines of file"
        },
        {
            "id": "20",
            "question": "tail -f file",
            "answer": "Output the contents of file as it grows, starting with the last 10 lines"
        },
        {
            "id": "21",
            "question": "create a new local repository",
            "answer": "git init [project name]"
        },
        {
            "id": "22",
            "question": "Download from an existing repository",
            "answer": "git clone my_url"
        },
        {
            "id": "23",
            "question": "List new or modified files not yet committed",
            "answer": "git status"
        },
        {
            "id": "24",
            "question": "Show the changes to files not yet staged",
            "answer": "git diff"
        },
        {
            "id": "25",
            "question": "Show the changes to staged files",
            "answer": "git diff --cached"
        },
        {
            "id": "26",
            "question": "Show all staged and unstaged file changes",
            "answer": "git diff HEAD"
        },
        {
            "id": "27",
            "question": "Show the cahnges between two commit ids",
            "answer": "git diff commit1 commit2"
        },
        {
            "id": "28",
            "question": "List the change dates and authors for a file",
            "answer": "git blame [file]"
        },
        {
            "id": "29",
            "question": "Show the file changes for a commit id and/or file",
            "answer": "git show [commit] : [file]"
        },
        {
            "id": "30",
            "question": "Show full change history",
            "answer": "git log"
        },
        {
            "id": "31",
            "question": "Show change history for file/directory including diffs",
            "answer": "git log -p [file/directory]"
        },
        {
            "id": "32",
            "question": "Stages the file,ready for commit",
            "answer": "git add [file]"
        },
        {
            "id": "33",
            "question": "Stage all changed files,ready for commit",
            "answer": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "34",
            "question": "Commit all staged files to versioned history",
            "answer": "git commit -m 'commit message'"
        },
        {
            "id": "35",
            "question": "Commit all your tracked files to versioned history",
            "answer": "git commit -am 'commit message'"
        },
        {
            "id": "36",
            "question": "Unstages file,keeping the file changes",
            "answer": "git reset [file]"
        },
        {
            "id": "37",
            "question": "Revert everything to the last commit",
            "answer": "git reset --hard"
        },
        {
            "id": "38",
            "question": "get the latest changes from origin(no merge)",
            "answer": "git fetch"
        },
        {
            "id": "39",
            "question": "Fetch the latest changes from origin and merge",
            "answer": "git pull"
        },
        {
            "id": "40",
            "question": "Fetch the latest changes from origin and rebase",
            "answer": "git pull --rebase"
        },
        {
            "id": "41",
            "question": "Push local changes to the origin",
            "answer": "git push"
        },
        {
            "id": "42",
            "question": "When in doubt,use git help",
            "answer": "git command --help"
        }
    ]
}